Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and we have a
delicious Italian food lesson for you today.
That's right, we are at an Italian
restaurant and we are ordering food.
So this is going to be
very helpful next time
you are at an Italian
restaurant with your
friends and you're
ordering up some dishes.
Let's take a listen to
our dialogue and we'll
be back in a moment to
talk about what's going on.
Good evening ladies, my name is
Josh and I'll be your servant tonight.
May I take your order?
Do you have any recommendations?
Well, I personally like
the chicken penner
with cream mushroom sauce, but
the prone fit the china is also very nice.
Oh no, I'd like to have
the grilled chicken,
but can I have spaghetti
instead of the china?
Of course man and for you.
I'll have the horse stripe.
All right, we're back and
now let's take a look at all
those delicious Italian
dishes on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So first of all, we have two
different kinds of sauce, really.
The first is cream mushroom,
so what's a cream sauce, Marco?
A cream mushroom
sauce, so basically this is
cream from like milk
and you have mushrooms
in it and I don't know,
I think everyone has
seen it, it's a very
thick white sauce, it
has little slices of mushrooms
in it, it's kind of sweet.
That's right and so
oftentimes you see there's
cream sauces which are white and tomato
sauces which are red, and this here is a
cream sauce, so it's white and it's got
chunks of mushroom in it, right, tasty.
And the waiter also offered pran
with the pasta, so what is a pran?
Pran fit a chini, so pran is like
a big, it's like a word for shrimp.
I always think of jumbo
prans which are these
big, big, big shrimp,
so they're basically
the same thing, shrimp and
pran are basically the same.
That's right, and
they're a seafood that
when they get cooked
they curl, so they look
like a circle but they're
pinkish or red, they're very tasty.
Okay, so now let's take
a look at the different
types of pasta, so we
have three different
types of pasta that
the waiter suggested, so
the first one is, okay,
we're going to say
all three in the American
way, but I'm going
to tell you the Italian
way is quite different,
so I'll say that afterwards,
the first is penny.
Okay, so this is a type of
pasta, what does it look like?
It is like a small tube,
so maybe maybe three
centimetres long, and
it is round and it has
a hole in the middle,
and so it's a kind of pasta.
And what about the fettuccini?
So fettuccini is a
long noodle, but it's
flat, it's flat, it's
flat, it's fettuccini.
So it kind of looks like a shoelace,
yeah, it's long and flat, okay.
And then we have
spaghetti, which I think many
people know, and this is
probably the most popular one.
That's right, spaghetti
is very long, just
like fettuccini, but it's
very, very thin and round.
So it kind of looks like
maybe a pencil, a very
long pencil, but very thin,
more like hair, actually.
Okay.
And there are thin
kinds, so they have a
special name, but this
is just a normal pasta
that you will see
everywhere, it's very long,
and you can twirl it, you
can spin it around your fork.
Okay, so that's what we have, we
have penne, fettuccini, and spaghetti.
Now, the other woman
ended up ordering horse
tripe, now this is also another
Italian dish, what is this exactly?
Well, horse is the
animal, so this is a,
this is a tripe that
comes from a horse, but
tripe is a certain part of the animal
that we, it's a food name actually.
So when we eat the
stomach lining, the part
of the stomach that
goes around the stomach,
it's kind of squishy, soft.
That is called tripe, and you can have
tripe from many different animals, like cows
or pigs, but in this
case, it's a horse tripe,
so it's basically that, that thick piece of
like spongy material around the animal's
stomach, when you
cook it, it looks very funny.
So this is, and this is actually a
famous Italian dish as well, right?
I think so, I think they ate it
in the south more, but you can
definitely get tripe in a lot
of different places in Italy.
Okay, very good.
So there you have
it, a lot of different
dishes, Italian dishes,
we've taken a look at
a couple of pasta dishes, why
don't we take a break, listen
to the dialogue again, and
we'll be back with fluency builder.
Good evening, ladies, my name is
Josh, and I'll be your servant tonight.
May I take your order?
May you have any recommendations?
Well, I personally like
the chicken penna with
cream mushroom sauce, but the
prawn fit the china is also very nice.
Oh no, I'd like to have
the grilled chicken,
but can I have spaghetti
instead of penne?
Of course, man, and for
you, I'll have the horse tripe.
All right, we're back,
so now we're going to
give you three key
phrases, fun fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So the phrases we have
selected for you today
are phrases that you
are sure to hear any
time you go to a
restaurant in America or any
other English-speaking
country, but basically
you have a waiter who comes to you if
you sit down, and this is what they'll say.
The first thing they'll
say is I'll be your server.
I'll be your server tonight.
So he introduces
himself, he says, "Good
evening ladies, my name is Josh,
and I'll be your server tonight."
So when he's saying,
"I'll be your server," it's
another way of saying,
"I'll be your waiter.
" They're waiter, that's
right, but server can
be a man or a woman, and
a waiter can only be a man.
If it's a woman, it's a waitress.
Okay, so waitress for a
woman, waiter for a guy,
but if you serve it, it's
for man and women.
Yes, I'll be your
server, and I just like to
remind you that this is
more common in America
because in America,
waiters, and waitresses,
or servers, they have to earn
tips, and so they're very nice.
Okay, so this is why they
introduce themselves.
They are very nice to you, and
then they ask, "May I take your order?
" May I take your order?
So the verb to take here
doesn't mean to take it from you.
It means to ask you, and
then they'll write it down.
Okay.
So the server will ask you what you want
to order, and then we'll write it down.
And the order is what you have decided
to eat, so that's the food that you order.
Now this next phrase
is very, very handy,
especially if you're in
a country that maybe
you don't know the
dish as well, or if you're
in a restaurant that
you want to see what
they recommend it, you can just say,
"Do you have any recommendations?
" Do you have any
recommendations?
Okay, so this is a way to
ask the server, "What's good?
" So what he thinks is good, or
what the restaurant serves very well.
Okay, so you could say, "I've
never been to this restaurant before.
Do you have any recommendations?
" Or maybe even Marco,
we're having dinner,
and I know that you
really like Italian food,
and I don't know much
about Italian food, so I
can ask you, "Do you
have any recommendations?
" Okay.
So this is a way of asking,
"What is good here?
What is delicious
in this restaurant?
" What's good to eat?
Okay.
All right.
So three phrases there
for you, why don't we
take another short
break, and let's listen
to the dialogue for the last time.
Good evening, ladies.
My name is Josh, and
I'll be your server tonight.
May I take your order?
Do you have any recommendations?
Well, I personally like
the chicken penner with
cream mushroom sauce, but the
prawn fit the china is also very nice.
No, no.
I'd like to have the grilled chicken, but
can I have spaghetti instead of the name?
Of course, man.
And for you.
I'll have the horse try.
All right.
So talking about pasta,
now, one thing before
you mentioned that
all these different types
of pasta, they're basically the same thing,
they're just different shapes, right?
That's how you distinguish them.
Well, yeah, they're
basically made from the
same ingredients, and
so you have, most of them
are kind of a yellow
color, but sometimes
you have pastas that
are a dark, like a brown
or a green, that depends on what kind
of things you put into the dough, right?
But generally, they're
the same ingredients,
but they are different
shapes, like they have
curly ones and they
long ones and short ones.
All right.
So it's pronounced, we
said, in English, in American
English, but in proper
Italian, it would be.
Penne.
So you double pronounced the consonant.
What about fettucini?
Fettucini.
Oh, it's fettucini.
In American, we say fettucini.
Fettucini.
Yeah.
Fettucini Alfredo is a
very common American
Italian dish, but in Italian
it would be fettucini.
So you might hear it differently.
And what about spaghetti?
Spaghetti.
Oh, you pronounce the double T as well.
That's right.
OK.
So you said that obviously there
are a lot of other types of pasta.
What about this pasta that
I think it's made of spinach?
It's green.
Yeah.
That's just a spinach pasta.
Oh, you just put the spinach in the dough.
But you can also find very many
shapes, like the angel hair pasta.
That's very thin.
It's very thin.
What I was saying is it's almost like hair,
it's so thin, it's very, it's long as well.
What about those little curly tubes?
They look like penne,
but they're kind of curved.
They look like little ends, or
you-- Oh, you have macaroni.
Macaroni.
Elbow macaroni.
We call them in America.
And they look like your elbow on your arms.
We call them elbow macaroni.
What about the ones that have a spiral?
They kind of look like springs.
Those are called fusili.
Fusili.
And you also have one that's very special.
This is my favorite pasta, by the way.
It's called Orakiette.
Oh, what is this?
Orakiette.
And they look like your ear.
And that's what that means in Italian.
It means your little ear.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
It's like ear pastas.
Wow.
And what about ravioli?
This is probably one of
the most famous dishes.
Ravioli.
What is this?
A ravioli is like a square pasta, but
it's more like a pocket or a pillow.
And inside, you have ingredients, like
meat or cheese usually is very popular.
So you have this cheese
inside, this little packet.
This little dough.
It's very soft, very warm.
And then on top,
sometimes people like to
put butter or tomato
sauce, really delicious.
So that's the main difference.
This was obviously
all the pasta that we
mentioned, they don't
have anything inside them.
No, they're just dough.
But ravioli is a
special kind of pasta
that's like a, it's almost
like a dumpling in a way.
It's stuffed.
It has something inside.
It's really interesting.
I think Italian cuisine is among one
of the most famous foods in the world.
And well, you should let us know
if, what is your favorite Italian dish?
Please let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com
and when you're
there, you could find out
what our favorite dishes are.
All right.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.